This task is about transforming a
list comprehension expression into an
expression using map, filter, and concat instead.
Therefore, we've been given, first of all,
an expression as a list comprehension.
This is a list of
pairs, and then we have the alternative
implementation, where we have to fill in the gaps.
Marked as undefined—where we
use map, filter, and concat.
For this task, we basically can define all
the parts by looking at what we require.
So there is the attempt to go sequentially
through the list comprehension,
but also there could be the attempt
of just looking at the types first.
Because we have been given the
functions concat; we know concat takes
a list of anything—well, it's a list of lists
of things—and turns it into a list of things.
Then when we look at this expression, you
see that the closing bracket is at the end:
so that's the argument for concat.
Then we have a map, and this map
has a first parameter which is
in these brackets, and the
second parameter which is a list.
Our first attempt could be just to
fill in arguments as the types fit.
We know that he is at some number 50, so we can
guess that we have to fill in any number here.
And in our original expression, we have two
of those things that we could insert; we can't
insert minus 50, and we could insert x.
Well, minus 50 is a concrete value which we could
insert in any place where we require
numbers, so it could be at those two gaps.
Obviously, it's not correct to place them
at both parts, because we know that we
have two different ranges of these lists.
But let's assume, first of all, we can
just fill in those parts like this.
Then we have filter.
Filter takes a function which is based on
a value of type a and returns a Boolean.
Our second argument is the
list of those integer values.
We want to return a Bool
based on the integer list.
Our first attempt could be to just ignore
the second argument, or the argument of the
filter, basically, and just return True always.
const True would return always
True, and we would filter nothing.
For map, we have to define again
something which returns what we require.
In this case, we have again as the
first argument something which turns
the argument into something else.
But this time, it's not like we filter
that; we have to return a Boolean—we
have to return something of type b so that
we get a list of type b when we apply map.
We have to think about what this b is.
Therefore, we have to go back and consider
what we get by using these functions around it.
So we have this map inside this lambda
expression here with x, and when we have a look:
this lambda—this lambda expression here
it ends here.
So it's basically the first argument
for the map which is then applied here.
With this list of -50 to 50.
Whatever we return here will be a
transformation of the list here.
We have to think about what filter
does: filter returns a list.
So we get a list here within the second
argument of map, which is a list of integers.
concat returns a list—or turns
a list of lists into a list.
What we return here
has to be, in fact, something which returns
tuples, because we want to have a list of tuples.
Let me, first of all, define
something here that is wrong.
So we can use again the const attempt and just say
we ignore the argument and then return something.
Let's just say we try to return the number
here, and in this case, the compiler will
return an error because we want to
have a pair of integer and integer,
which is not possible by just giving a 1 here.
So we have to return a pair of integers.
And what could these be—these integers?
We have one which we get
from the filter here back, and we have one
that is defined before; that is the x here.
So we could simply return those two.
Now let me load this program in the GHCi.
And now we get a list which
is not correct yet, but
actually, the types fit, our program compiles,
and we can have a first attempt at using it.
We get a lot of values back.
When we compare this to our original,
then we see some differences because
there were—here are just positive
values at the end in the original, and
the alternative gives us some negative
values as well in the last set here.
We can use main as well,
which gives us a test case for
comparing those two lists,
and this one here is this.
It uses take, so we can use this argument in
order to see the error which is happening here.
So we say take 66 from original and take 66 from
alternative; then we see that at this point here
both lists differ, so here's minus 49
and -49, and here's 50 and (plus) 15.
Okay. Now we can look at what we have done
here within our definition of the alternative.
Of course, we know one of these is wrong.
We have -50 here, and we have -50
here, and one of these has to be x.
And which one is it?
Well, we can now look at the approach of
going right through the list comprehension,
which could have been our first attempt as well.
If we start converting this list comprehension
expression, then we see that we have
first of all these running over all
the x values coming from this list.
This is expressed by using the map.
Its second argument is exactly
this list here—from -50 to 50.
So we can use this range expression here in
order to retrieve the x values as before.
Then we use the lambda expression
here in the first part of the map.
This lambda expression continues to be
the other parts of the list comprehension.
The next part is retrieving
all the values from x to 50.
We have again a map here in order to do this.
The map has a first argument
and it has a second argument.
In the second argument—well, that's
a bit richer expression here.
Because at the end we have what we want to
range over, which are the values from x to 50.
That's because filter is applied to that list
and filter does what this expression here does.
This is a filter expression because we
have no left arrow there at this part and
this is no let expression -
so this just filters the list.
This part shall be ranging from x to something
and this part here is our filter expression.
This filter expression is a
function taking one argument in this
concrete example here it is our y.
Because that's what we get here in our expression
it's y, which ranges over from x to 50.
This is the first part here y.
Then we apply simply this filter here.
It's abs of x plus y is greater than
35 - this is our filter expression.
Then there's just one part missing
which is implemented already and
that's this creation of the tuple.
We can simply create the tuple by
applying our map on that filtered list.
Which is what we get by
applying this filter, right?
We applied this filter to the values
of x and y in this case here.
And we apply another function using
map, that's what's written here!
This function takes first of
all the y and because we are
in a map already and have the x value
already, we can just create a tuple.
We get the expression that we
created in our list comprehension.
If we now take 66 from alternative and 66 from
original we get the same values here at these places.
And when we apply the tests, then we get to the
same result and we are done with solving the task.
Some of you may have seen within Autotool that it
suggested using a tuple section in this case here.
So it says you can replace the
function of y with triple x y by just
applying x, comma, and
closing bracket, i.e., (,x).
If this would look like this, you can write
this in Autotool and it will accept the answer.
If you write this locally in your
ghci it will probably reject the
file loading, saying there you use a
tuple section which is not allowed.
It would be required to tell ghci to use
tuple sections and then you are allowed
to apply this trick locally as well.
But in Autotool you can just send in this answer!
And it would be fine when
using this tuple section.
That's what the comment said which you probably
might have seen when you had this here.
Then Autotool suggests using a tuple section
here, but this is just a side remark.